LUCAS HAWK

630-777-2786 lucaswhawk@gmail.com

635 Main Street Carlisle, Iowa 50047

Profile

With over 15 years making artwork, products, and media for companies from concept to production, I bring a design and manufacturing background to web development. I've been a graphic designer, illustrator, art director, creative director, and now a web designer and developer.

Skills

UI-UX design, restful apps from scratch. Javascript, AngularJS, Node, SQL, JQuery, HTML, CSS, SASS/SCSS, Gulp, Bootstrap, GiHub, D3. Expert user of Illustrator, Indesign, Photoshop. Automation using Applescript and Javascript for production and media. Practical knowledge of many physical production processes and methods, including automation of Adobe products, email, and workflow across programs.

Education

Dev Mountain, Provo Utah University of Northern Iowa, Fine Arts Graphic Design Emphasis

Experience

Freelance Designer, Web Developer — 2014-present

- Traveled to companies in Canada and the U.S. to implement Applescript workflows to improve design department efficiency as much as 400%
- Created catalogs, illustrations, fliers, apparel (screen print, embroidery, full dye sublimation), websites, e-mail blasts, corporate identities, and packaging
- Attended Dev Mountain to learn AngularJS, advanced Javascript, jQuery, Node, SQL, Mongoose, and other technologies
- Switched freelance work almost exclusively to web at the beginning of this year. Made two websites for local businesses, and am involved in projects with other developers.

Creative Director, Boombah, Yorkville, II - 2013-2014

- Managed personnel, creative and production output, and cross departmental projects of Art Department
- Managed switch from Corel Draw and PCs to Illustrator and Macs
- Created and wrote manuals for screen print and full dye production processes
- Led the creation of 3,980 new pieces of art for new line releases

Art Director, J-America Sportswear, Webberville, Mi — 2007-2013

- Developed six yearly line releases and support materials, including catalogs, mailers, and point of purchase materials
- Increased production art's output by 380% and creative art's by 150% by improving practices and scripting repetitive tasks
- Eliminated 60% of production art's daily workload with scripting, improved templates, and training
- Created best-selling screen print and embroidery designs
- Increased production of sales materials and presentations by 200% while improving overall quality
- Standardized practices, wrote company manual, and trained staff
- Designed, stocked, and built trade show booths for four annual trade shows

Graphic Artist, Adidas, Indianapolis, In — 2006-2007

- Created t-shirt graphic templates
- Worked with NHL licensing to maintain several brands' focus
- Streamlined production art, approvals, and proofing with Applescript
- Created standards for and wrote portions of the screen print manual

References

Jim McCollough - VP of Sales - Edwards Garment ph: 269-910-7440 jmccollough@edwardsgarment.com

Janie Darby - Designer 2 - Adidas

9ph: 989-996-0533 janie.darby@adidas-group.com